Fast cars. Fast girls. Fast living.
Roadracers is a action, crime, drama film directed by Robert Rodriguez.
In the 1950s, guitar-playing drifter Dude Delaney wanders into a quiet town looking to play music and
generally cause trouble, much to the chagrin of the local sheriff, known as Sarge.
While palling around with his B-movie-obsessed friend Nixer, Dude meets the beautiful Donna, and is offered a
position in a rockabilly band, but the sheriff is intent on getting rid of him by any means necessary.
Dude Delaney, played by David Arquette.
Donna, played by Salma Hayek Pinault.
Nixer, played by John Hawkes.
Teddy Leather, played by Jason Wiles.
J.T., played by O'Neal Compton.
Miles, played by Kevin McCarthy.
Roadracers is a 1994 made-for-television film directed by Robert Rodriguez, his
second feature film following the success of his 1992 debut, El Mariachi.
The film originally aired on Showtime Network as part of their Rebel Highway series that took the titles of 1950s-era B-movies and applied them to original films starring up-and-coming
actors of the 1990s (including the likes of Alicia Silverstone and Shannen Doherty) and directed by established directors such as William Friedkin, Joe Dante, and Ralph Bakshi.
Rodriguez was the only young director to participate in the series.
The series was produced by the son and daughter of Samuel Z.
Arkoff, the co-founder and producer of American International Pictures (AIP),
the distributor of the films this series takes its titles from.
Robert Rodriguez's take concerned a rebel named Dude Delaney (David Arquette) who dreams of leaving his dead end small town and becoming a
rockabilly star but gets caught up in a nasty feud with the town's local sheriff (William Sadler) and his son (Jason Wiles).
Salma Hayek plays Dude's girlfriend, Donna.
The film explores themes of car race, texas,
juvenile delinquent, 1950s, young girl.
The tone is emotional and intense.